- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- * Ohh...
- * 哦...
* Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? *
*谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ *
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he *
- * 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * If nautical nonsense
be something you wish *
- *如果航海废话
成为你所希望的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish *
- * 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通 *
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
*
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
*
[upbeat rock music playing]
[欢快的摇滚乐演奏]
[horn honking]
- Huh?
[喇叭鸣响]
- 啊？
[gasps]
[喘气]
It's here!
Yee-haw!
就在这里！
呀呀！
My newest science book
has arrived.
我最新的科学书
已经到了。
I wonder what new and fantastic
area of science
我想知道有什么新奇的东西
科学领域
will be revealed to me
this month.
将向我透露
这个月。
Oh, hey, it's them
fancy bloomers I ordered too.
哦，嘿，是他们
我也订购了精美的灯笼裤。
This day just keeps
getting better.
这一天就这样持续着
越来越好。
Ah.
啊。
"Behavioral psychology
《行为心理学
is the study of people
and their habits."
是对人的研究
以及他们的习惯。”
I've studied
underwater chemistry,
我学过
水下化学,
geology, and astronomy,
地质学、天文学、
but I've never studied
underwater people.
但我从来没有学过
水下的人。
Sandy Cheeks,
day one of behavioral study
桑迪脸颊，
行为研究的第一天
of subjects
in Bikini Bottom.
科目数
在比基尼底部。
Initiating observations...
now!
开始观察...
现在！
- My wife said
she wouldn't even try it,
- 我妻子说
她甚至都不会尝试
no matter how much
I salt the legumes.
无论多少
我给豆类加盐。
- My daughter Amanda
is exactly the same.
- 我的女儿阿曼达
是完全一样的。
It's always
an argument.
总是这样
一个论点。
I mean,
I've tried to--
我的意思是，
我尝试过——
- Older lumpy-looking
female subject,
- 较旧的块状外观
女性主体，
obviously a mother,
hates daughter.
明明是一位母亲，
讨厌女儿。
- Excuse me!
- 打扰一下！
- Subject asked
to be excused,
- 对象询问
可以原谅,
but I am unable to observe what
she wishes to be excused from.
但我无法观察到什么
她希望得到原谅。
- Hey, creepy squirrel,
- 嘿，令人毛骨悚然的松鼠，
what's with all
the eavesdropping?
怎么了
窃听？
- Take a hike, mammal!
- 徒步旅行吧，哺乳动物！
- Subjects' emotional state
seems to be rising in anger.
- 受试者的情绪状态
似乎怒火中烧。
Eyebrows are now
considerably furrowed.
现在眉毛
明显皱起。
- [grunting]
- [screaming]
- [咕哝]
- [尖叫]
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
I got to find new subjects...
我得寻找新的课题...
who won't mind
being observed.
谁不介意
被观察。
[laughter]
[笑声]
Eureka!
尤里卡！
- Hey, that's my line.
- 嘿，这是我的台词。
[laughter]
[笑声]
- Hey, fellas.
- 嘿，伙计们。
How'd you like to be a part
of my cool experiment?
你想成为其中的一员吗
我的酷实验？
- [exhales deeply]
- [深呼气]
Ooh, I could use a mint.
Mmm.
哦，我可以用薄荷糖。
嗯。
- No, Patrick.
- 不，帕特里克。
It's an experiment
in behavioral psychology.
这是一个实验
在行为心理学中。
- That doesn't
sound tasty.
- 那不
听起来很好吃。
- What do we have
to do?
- 我们有什么
做什么？
- It's easy.
- 这很容易。
I observe you
while you two act normal.
我观察你
而你们两个却表现得很正常。
- Act normal?
- Yeah.
- 表现正常吗？
- 是的。
Just do what you
would naturally do.
做你该做的事
自然会做。
Be natural.
保持自然。
Starting...now!
开始……现在！
- Uh, natural greeting
to you, friend.
- 呃，自然的问候
给你，朋友。
- Natural greeting
returned.
- 自然的问候
回来了。
- Would you like
to have some natural fun?
- 你愿意吗
享受一些自然的乐趣？
- Oh, yes, please.
- 哦，是的，请。
- Naturally.
[babbling]
- 当然。
[胡说]
- Ugh, all right.
Experiment's done.
- 呃，好吧。
实验完成了。
- Oh, oh, oh, oh,
oh, oh, oh, oh!
- 哦，哦，哦，哦，
哦，哦，哦，哦！
What are the results?
结果如何？
- [laughing]
Did we do good?
- [笑]
我们做得好吗？
- Oh, can I have
an A-plus?
- 哦，我可以吗
A+？
- Oh, oh, yes!
I want an A-plus too!
- 哦，哦，是的！
我也想要一个A+！
Oh! Pretty please,
pretty please, pretty please?
哦！ Pretty please,
请漂亮，请漂亮？
- Pretty please
with sugar on top?
- 拜托了
上面有糖吗？
- Yes, yes.
- 是的，是的。
You both get
an A-plus.
你们都得到
A+。
- Whoo!
- I knew it!
- 呼！
- 我就知道！
- Whoo!
- 呼！
- Subjects acting natural.
Resume observation.
- 拍摄对象表现自然。
恢复观察。
- Aha.
- I got an A-plus!
- 啊哈。
- 我得了 A+！
both: A-plus, A-plus, A-plus.
A-plus, A-plus, A-plus.
两者：A+，A+，A+。
A+，A+，A+。
- Oh, forget it.
-哦，算了。
[laughter]
[笑声]
"When a subject is aware
of being observed,
“当一个主体意识到
被观察到的，
it can affect his or her actions
and create inaccurate data."
它会影响他或她的行为
并创建不准确的数据。”
Hmm.
唔。
- [babbling]
- [胡言乱语]
- Double eureka!
- 双重尤里卡！
both: That's our line!
两人：这就是我们的路线！
- Hey, are you guys up
for another experiment?
- 嘿，你们起来了吗
进行另一个实验？
- Oh, boy, am I ever!
- 哦，孩子，我曾经吗！
Can you hook us up
to electrodes
你能联系我们吗
至电极
or--or expose us
to gamma rays?
或者——或者揭露我们
伽马射线？
- Ehhh...
- 呃...
- It's a guaranteed
A-plus.
- 这是有保证的
A+。
- Oh!
It's like a dream!
- 哦！
这就像一个梦！
- Okay, first thing.
- 好的，第一件事。
Go to the beach
and fill one bucket
去海滩
并装满一桶
with white sand
有白沙
and one bucket
with black sand.
和一桶
与黑沙。
Can you do that?
- Easy sneezy!
你能做到吗？
- 容易打喷嚏！
- [sneezes]
- [打喷嚏]
- Eww.
- Eh...
- 呃。
- 呃...
Yeah,
whatever he said.
是的，
不管他说什么。
- Then off you go.
[laughter]
- 那你就走吧。
[笑声]
Time to get to work.
是时候去上班了。
[spy music]
[间谍音乐]
*
- Sandy!
- 桑迪！
We're back.
我们回来了。
- Good job, fellers!
- 干得好，伙计们！
- We're an awesome team!
- We sure are, buddy.
- 我们是一支很棒的团队！
- 我们当然是，伙计。
- Okay, team,
- 好吧，团队，
for this experiment,
I need you to count
对于这个实验，
我需要你数数
the grains of sand
in each bucket,
沙粒
每个桶中，
then tell me if there are
more black grains
然后告诉我是否有
更多黑色颗粒
or more white grains,
或更多白色颗粒，
or is it the same amount?
或者是相同的数量？
All right, then.
好吧，那么。
I have to run some errands,
but I'll be back later.
我还得办点事
但我稍后会回来。
- [laughs]
Aye, aye, Captain Sandy.
- [笑]
是的，是的，桑迪船长。
- Oh, and, Patrick,
you're in charge.
- 哦，还有，帕特里克，
你负责。
- Oh...
- 哦...
[blipping]
[闪烁]
- All systems check.
- 所有系统检查。
- Well, let's get counting.
- 好吧，让我们来数数。
Should we both
count white sand
我们俩应该吗
数白沙
and move on
to the black sand,
并继续前进
到黑沙，
or do you want to have
your own bucket?
或者你想拥有
你自己的水桶？
- I'm in charge.
I'm in charge.
- 我负责。
我负责。
I'm in charge.
- So what's it gonna be,
boss?
- 那会是什么，
老板？
- Uh...the first one?
- 呃...第一个？
- [laughs]
You're in charge.
- [笑]
你负责。
- I'm in charge.
- One...
- 我负责。
- 一...
[clears throat]
- I'm in charge.
[清嗓子]
- 我负责。
Two...
二...
- Three.
- I'm in charge.
- 三。
- 我负责。
I'm in charge.
我负责。
- 47.
47?
47？
- 47.
- Uh? Huh? What?
- 呃？啊？什么？
- Lost you there
for a little bit.
- 在那里失去了你
一点点。
We were at 47?
我们当时47岁？
- I don't know if I want
to do it this way.
- 我不知道我是否想要
这样做。
- Okay, boss man,
how do you want to do it?
- 好的，老板，
- Uh...
oh, oh...
- 呃...
哦，哦...
- How about you count
the white sand
- 你数一下怎么样
白沙
and I count
the black sand?
我数数
黑沙？
- Yeah!
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
- 是的！
是啊，是啊，是啊，是啊。
That's it.
就是这样。
48, forty...nine!
48、四十九！
Oh, oh, 50!
哦哦，50！
One, two, three, four, five,
six, seven...
一、二、三、四、五、
六、七……
- Seven...
both: Eight, nine, ten.
- 七...
两者：八、九、十。
- Oh!
- 哦！
- Time to initiate
the first variable.
- 启动时间
第一个变量。
One big bowl,
one small bowl.
一大碗，
一小碗。
Exactly eight ounces
per bowl.
正好八盎司
每碗。
Free ice-a cream.
Free ice-a cream!
免费冰淇淋。
免费冰淇淋！
A-one day only!
啊、仅限一天！
Get your free-a ice cream!
免费获得一份冰淇淋！
- Oh, boy!
Let's go!
- 哦，孩子！
我们走吧！
- You're the boss.
- Free ice-a cream-a!
- 你是老板。
- 免费冰淇淋！
- Oh, my sea stars,
free ice cream.
- 哦，我的海星，
免费冰淇淋。
- Hey, boys.
- 嘿，孩子们。
How'd you like
a nice-a free-a bowl
你觉得怎么样
不错-免费-一碗
of tuttsi fruitsi
ice-a cream-a?
图西水果的
冰淇淋-a？
[both panting]
[两人都气喘吁吁]
Okey-a-dokey.
好吧。
- One free ice cream,
please.
- 一份免费冰淇淋，
请。
- All sold out.
Maybe we'll get some later!
- 全部卖完了。
也许我们稍后会得到一些！
- Ow!
- 噢！
[grumbling]
[抱怨]
Lousy first come,
first serve.
先到先得，
首先发球。
- Um, your--your bowl
is bigger.
- 嗯，你的——你的碗
更大。
- You want to trade?
- Yeah.
- 你想交易吗？
- 是的。
- Hmm?
Mm-mm...
- 唔？
嗯嗯……
You got more ice cream.
你还有更多的冰淇淋。
- Patrick, I think your
ice cream only looks smaller
- 帕特里克，我想你的
冰淇淋只是看起来更小
'cause the bowl is big.
因为碗很大。
- Well, I want
to trade back.
- 嗯，我想要
来交易回来。
There's only
one fair thing to do.
只有
一件公平的事情要做。
- What's that?
- 那是什么？
Patrick,
you call that fair?
帕特里克，
你说这公平吗？
- I'm in charge.
- 我负责。
- Ah...
Oh, yeah.
- 啊...
哦，是的。
- Time for variable two.
- 变量二的时间。
More free-a ice cream here.
更免费——这里有冰淇淋。
Now in-a same sized cones.
现在处于相同大小的锥体中。
- Huh?
I just got my slippers on.
- 啊？
我刚穿上拖鞋。
- Here you go!
- I'll take those, my good man.
- 干得好！
- 我会接受的，我的好人。
- Oh, but, Patrick, I--
- I'm in charge.
- 哦，但是，帕特里克，我——
- 我负责。
- Uh, one cone, please.
- All gone!
- 呃，请给我一个甜筒。
- 全部消失了！
- Ow!
- 噢！
[grumbling]
[抱怨]
For the love of Pete!
为了皮特的爱！
- Can I have my cone now?
Can I have my cone now?
- 我现在可以拿我的甜筒吗？
我现在可以拿我的甜筒吗？
Can I have my cone now?
- Mm...
hmm...
- 嗯...
嗯...
Rub my feet first.
- Oh, come on!
先揉脚。
- 哦，来吧！
- Who's in charge?
- All right, I'll rub your feet.
- 谁负责？
- 好吧，我给你擦脚。
Eww.
呃。
Hey, my ice cream is melting
all over your hand.
嘿，我的冰淇淋融化了
遍布你的手。
- Oh...
I'll fix that.
- 哦...
我会解决这个问题。
- Patrick, you are making
very poor choices!
- 帕特里克，你正在做
非常糟糕的选择！
- Don't you back-sass me!
- 你别跟我顶嘴！
I'm in charge,
我负责，
and you have to do
what I say.
你必须做
我说什么。
Now...count that bucket
of white sand.
现在...数一下那个桶
白色的沙子。
- All right,
I will.
- 好吧，
我会的。
1,893,601,
1,893,602,
1,893,603.
1,893,603。
Done!
Now to count the black sand.
完毕！
现在来数一下黑沙。
- Oh, that's a pity.
- 噢，真可惜。
Looks like you'll have
to start over.
看起来你会有
重新开始。
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
Enjoying that ice cream,
Patrick?
一边享受着那份冰淇淋，
帕特里克？
- Yes, I am.
- 我是。
- Would you like
sprinkles on it?
- 你愿意吗
洒在上面吗？
- Hey!
- 嘿！
- Jeepers,
I didn't see that coming.
- 吉普车，
我没有预见到这一点。
- You don't leave
until I say so!
-你别离开
直到我这么说！
[both growling]
[双方咆哮]
- Sandy to Gary,
Sandy to Gary,
- 桑迪对加里说，
桑迪对加里说：
how serious
is the situation?
多么严重
情况如何？
- [mewling]
- [呜咽]
- Oh, I didn't think this
all the way through.
-哦，我没想到这个
一路过去。
I've got to shut this down!
我必须把这个关掉！
[alarm buzzing]
[警报声响起]
- Aha!
I want my free--
- 啊哈！
我想要我的自由——
- Open the door!
The experiment is over!
- 打开门！
实验结束了！
Open the door!
开门！
- You heard Sandy.
Open the door!
- 你听到桑迪的话了。
开门！
- You open it!
- No, you open it!
- 你打开它！
- 不，你打开它！
- No, you open it!
[explosion]
- 不，你打开它！
[爆炸]
- Mr. Pavlovi,
tell SpongeBob to open the door!
- 巴甫洛维先生，
告诉海绵宝宝开门！
- It's me, Sandy!
- 是我，桑迪！
The experiment is over!
实验结束了！
- But we didn't even finish
counting the sand.
- 但我们还没完成
数沙子。
- I didn't care
about the sand.
- 我不在乎
关于沙子。
I just wanted to observe you
acting naturally,
我只是想观察你
表现自然，
so I hid microphones and cameras
around your house--
所以我隐藏了麦克风和摄像头
你家周围——
both: Cameras?
两人：相机？
- Et tu, Gary?
- 你呢，加里？
- [meows]
- [喵]
- [crying]
- [哭泣]
I was a monster.
我是一个怪物。
I deserve a C-minus.
我应该得到 C-。
- Aw, Patrick, don't be
so hard on yourself.
- 噢，帕特里克，别这样
对自己太苛刻了。
It was the experiment's fault
that you were such a jerk.
这是实验的错
你真是个混蛋。
- I blame science,
stupid science.
- 我责怪科学，
愚蠢的科学。
- Everybody gets
an A-plus
- 每个人都得到
A+
and-a ice-a cream-a!
还有-一个冰-一个奶油-一个！
[both laughing and cheering]
[又笑又欢呼]
- [grumbles]
- [抱怨]
What is going on?
到底是怎么回事？
I know it's
a stupid question,
我知道这是
一个愚蠢的问题，
but is there
any ice cream left?
但有吗
还有冰淇淋吗？
- Oh...eesh,
sorry, we're all out.
- 哦...哎呀，
抱歉，我们都出去了。
- You ate it all?
You animals!
- 你都吃完了吗？
你们这些动物！
You didn't even leave me
one drop?
你甚至没有离开我
一滴？
There's got to be
some left in here!
一定有
有些还留在这儿！
[crying]
[哭泣]
- Now let the real
experiment begin.
- 现在让真正的
实验开始。
- Come on!
Get in my mouth!
- 快点！
快到我嘴里来吧！
Oh, this one's empty!
哦，这个是空的！
[soft tropical music]
[轻柔的热带音乐]